<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://p.foundation/messages</id>
    <title>P Foundation Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-10-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://p.foundation/messages"/>
    <subtitle>P Foundation Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://p.foundation/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conflict Connectivity: Urgent Donor Call]]></title>
        <id>https://p.foundation/messages/conflict_connectivity_donor_call</id>
        <link href="https://p.foundation/messages/conflict_connectivity_donor_call"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the wake of escalating tensions and recent events in Gaza, we are increasingly concerned about the high likelihood of a military conflict erupting between Israel and Lebanon.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2><p>Founded in 2021 and duly recognized as a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization based in Washington, DC, the P Foundation is anchored in a strong conviction about the transformative power of media and technology. We are unwaveringly committed to fostering progress and uplifting the communities we serve. Central to our mission is the philosophy that an open internet and unrestricted journalism serve as the lifeblood of progressive societies, weaving together the essential elements of transparency, accountability, and unfettered expression.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="situation-overview">Situation Overview<a href="#situation-overview" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Situation Overview" title="Direct link to Situation Overview">​</a></h2><p>In the wake of escalating tensions and recent events in Gaza, we are increasingly concerned about the high likelihood of a military conflict erupting between Israel and Lebanon.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="infrastructure-concerns">Infrastructure Concerns<a href="#infrastructure-concerns" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Infrastructure Concerns" title="Direct link to Infrastructure Concerns">​</a></h2><p>Possessing an in-depth understanding of Lebanon's Internet Infrastructure, we project that even without targeted attacks on vital internet nodes and in the absence of a national diesel reserve, most local exchange points are at risk of depleting their diesel reserves. Should this occur, a widespread internet blackout across Lebanon would be inevitable within one to two weeks.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-initiative">Our Initiative<a href="#our-initiative" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Initiative" title="Direct link to Our Initiative">​</a></h2><p>While we have successfully secured funds for our Media Guard Emergency Plan, we are actively seeking immediate donors to contribute to our Community Mesh Program.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="importance-of-communication">Importance of Communication<a href="#importance-of-communication" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Importance of Communication" title="Direct link to Importance of Communication">​</a></h2><p>Given the displacement of populations and the extreme stress associated with wartime conditions, maintaining communication lines and internet access will become indispensable for residents to stay connected both within and beyond the country's borders.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="program-expansion">Program Expansion<a href="#program-expansion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Program Expansion" title="Direct link to Program Expansion">​</a></h2><p>As we await the final authorizations to deploy temporary satellite internet access, we aim to broaden the reach of our Community Mesh Program by integrating an additional 150 communities.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="technical-specifications">Technical Specifications<a href="#technical-specifications" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Technical Specifications" title="Direct link to Technical Specifications">​</a></h2><p>Each community will be equipped with a compact satellite dish for internet access and a Wi-Fi access point capable of supporting up to 300 devices simultaneously. The system is powered by solar panels and supplemented with a small battery, enabling limited nighttime usage.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="operational-management">Operational Management<a href="#operational-management" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Operational Management" title="Direct link to Operational Management">​</a></h2><p>Depending on the location, the management and upkeep of the mesh will be delegated either to the local municipality or a partnering non-profit organization. Volunteers will be stationed to ensure stable access and offer any required guidance to the public.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="geographical-distribution">Geographical Distribution<a href="#geographical-distribution" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Geographical Distribution" title="Direct link to Geographical Distribution">​</a></h2><p>We intend to deploy these mesh networks in densely populated regions like Beirut, Mount Lebanon, and North Lebanon, based on multiple criteria. The public will be informed of the mesh locations via our website or through a dedicated local phone number.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="capacity-limitations">Capacity Limitations<a href="#capacity-limitations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Capacity Limitations" title="Direct link to Capacity Limitations">​</a></h2><p>Should the demand surpass our current capabilities, we plan to rotate the mesh networks among various locations, thus maximizing the number of people who can gain internet access.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="post-conflict-utility">Post-Conflict Utility<a href="#post-conflict-utility" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Post-Conflict Utility" title="Direct link to Post-Conflict Utility">​</a></h2><p>Once the local infrastructure begins to recover post-conflict, these mesh networks can be reallocated to areas still experiencing service interruptions. Ultimately, these devices will be repurposed to augment our ongoing Community Mesh Program, providing internet access to schools and other public institutions in need.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="urgent-call-to-action">Urgent Call to Action<a href="#urgent-call-to-action" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Urgent Call to Action" title="Direct link to Urgent Call to Action">​</a></h2><p>We are racing against time; the most pressing challenge is to acquire the necessary equipment and transport it to Lebanon before a conflict commences and potential airport closures occur. While we have managed to make the requisite down payments for the satellite dishes, we are urgently seeking $350,000 to finalize implementation and sustain 90 days of service.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jud Saoud</name>
            <email>jud@p.foundation</email>
        </author>
        <category label="donor-support" term="donor-support"/>
        <category label="community-mesh" term="community-mesh"/>
    </entry>
</feed>